Accessing JSON files in Python is just like accessing dictionaries and lists in Python.
بالوصول إلى ملفات JSON في Python يشبه تمامًا الوصول إلى القواميس والقوائم في Python.
That's because JSON objects are interpreted as dictionaries
وذلك لأن كائنات JSON يتم تفسيرها كقواميس
and JSON arrays are interpreted as lists. Using the E.T.
وصفائف JSON يتم تفسيرها كقوائم. باستخدام صندوق معلومات E.T.
Wikipedia info box example,
Wikipedia على سبيل المثال،
which I have here loaded as a JSON object.
الذي قمت بتحميله هنا في صورة كائن JSON.
Let's access a few pieces of data within this object.
دعونا الوصول إلى بضع قطع من البيانات داخل هذا الكائن.
And there is the Box Office figure using bracket notation:
وهناك رمز شباك التذاكر باستخدام علامة الأقواس:
$792,900,000 and here's the Produced by key,
792,900,000 دولارًا وهنا المنتج الذي أنتجته بالمفتاح،
which returns a JSON array, which is like a list.
والذي يرجع صفيف JSON، الذي يشبه قائمة.
The zero index should be Kathleen Kennedy and the first index should be Steven Spielberg.
يجب أن يكون مؤشر الصفر كاثلين كينيدي ويجب أن يكون المؤشر الأول ستيفن سبيلبرغ.
And here's the release key whose value is a JSON array of JSON objects.
وهنا مفتاح الإطلاق الذي قيمته مصفوفة JSON لكائن JSON.
The first object in the array has the May 26 release date and the location being
يحتوي الكائن الأول في المصفوفة على تاريخ إصدار 26 مايو والمكان الذي به
Cannes and the second object in the array has the June 11th release date for the USA.
مهرجان كان والكائن الثاني في المصفوفة التي لها تاريخ إصدار 11 يونيو للولايات المتحدة الأمريكية.
This is just an object so we can access these keys using bracket notation again.
هذا مجرد كائن حتى نتمكن من الوصول إلى هذه المفاتيح باستخدام علامات الأقواس مرة أخرى.
With API's, JSON, and downloading files from the Internet now under your belt,
باستخدام API، وJSON، وتنزيل الملفات من الإنترنت الآن تحت حزامك،
you now have all of the knowledge required to download all of the movie poster images.
لديك الآن كل المعلومات المطلوبة لتنزيل كل صور ملصق الفيلم.
You're going to do that next and it's going to be pretty, pretty cool.
ستفعل ذلك بعد ذلك وستكون جميلة جدًا.